Hi, I'm Breis and I'm going to show you
right now how to perform an eccentric
quasi isometric or an EQI with the um
with the static lunge. So um I learned
this from my friend Jeremy Fritz and he
has a unique way of doing these. It's
really effective. So you're going to get
in
a take a really long stride. You want
your shin to be vertical. So, you don't
want to be leaning backward or forward.
Make sure it's straight. You're going to
plant or flex your ankle and you're
going to pull rearward as hard as you
can. And then you want this hip flexor
to be stretched. And you're squeezing
this glute as hard as possible. So, I'm
pulling in with my hamstring of this leg
as hard as possible and squeezing the
glute of this leg as hard as possible.
So, here's what it looks
like. down. Squeezing this glute,
pulling this in as hard as I
can, as hard as you possibly can. I'll
hold it for 30 seconds and then switch
and do it with the other leg. So, give
it a try. That's a really good
variation.